Take a New Year Cruise to Rio with the Screen's Top Laughter Trio!
Road to Rio is a comedy, adventure, music film directed by Norman Z. McLeod.
Scat Sweeney and Hot Lips Barton, two out of work musicians, stow away onboard a ship
bound for Rio, after accidentally setting fire to the big top of a circus.
They then get mixed up with a potential suicide Lucia, who first thanks
them, then unexpectedly turns them over to the ship's captain.
When they find out that she has been hypnotized, to go through a marriage of convenience, when the ship reaches
Rio, the boys turn up at the ceremony, in order to stop the wedding, and to help catch the crooks.
Scat Sweeney, played by Bing Crosby.
Hot Lips Barton, played by Bob Hope.
Lucia Maria de Andrade, played by Dorothy Lamour.
Catherine Vail, played by Gale Sondergaard.
Trigger, played by Frank Faylen.
Tony, played by Joseph Vitale.
Road to Rio is a 1947 American musical comedy film directed by Norman Z.
McLeod and starring Bing Crosby, Bob Hope, and Dorothy Lamour.
Written by Edmund Beloin and Jack Rose, the film is about two inept
vaudevillians who stow away on a Brazilian-bound ocean liner.
Once in Brazil, they foil a plot by a sinister hypnotist to
marry off her niece to a greedy fortune hunter.
Road to Rio was the fifth of the "Road to ..." series.
The film explores themes of ship, rio de janeiro,
musical, black and white, road movie.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.